# UMUT AKTAŞ

## aktasumut@gmail.com +90 533 599 6771, +7 916 439 8168 Moscow (RU) - Ankara (TR)

### PROFILE

Graduated from Strive School AI master camp.

6 years background in mechanical engineering - design engineering, mathematical modeling, 3D design programming, project management.

Want to use my old and new skills in IT as an engineer, analyst, or project manager.

### **KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python	NLP	REST API
Scikit Learn	LSTM, CNN	Flask
Tensorflow	Web Scraping	Docker
PyTorch	Computer Vision	AWS

Feature Engineering SQL Microsoft Azure

## PROJECT MANAGEMENT SKILLS

COLOT MANAGEMENT SKILLS			
Microsoft Project Jira Power BI	Tableau SAP CRM Lean	Budgeting Resource planning Materials planning	

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

## Strive School (Y Combinator)

### Strive Tutor 06.2021 - Present

Helping new master camp students with their projects and tasks on the points of arranging the knowledge base, feature engineering, deep learning, and machine learning algorithms.

## MAN (Subordinate of Volkswagen)

### **Project Manager 06.2020 - 12.2020 (7 months)**

Nonserial and limited series bus production.

Coordinated crisis teams focused on solving production failures in 33 minute takt time (more than 600 failures monthly).

Managed cost, human, time resources, and agreements for projects.

Leaded project teams of 10 to 20 people.

Mediated inter-departmental issues and crisis agreements.

Wrote functional requirements and algorithms for IT solutions in the area of responsibility

#### Mechanical Workability Engineer 12.2019 - 02.2021 (14 months)

Coordinated instant crisis teams for solving production failures, up to 6 people.

Developed permanent solutions for typical production problems using the root cause method.

Trained junior engineers, 12 mentees.

## **Senior Design Engineer 09.2016 - 08.2019 (3 years)**

Designed kinematic parts of the vehicles according to customer change requests.

Organized design thinking sessions, knowledge management bases, and prioritized the solutions. Coordinated interdisciplinary international project teams with colleagues from Poland, Germany, and Turkev.

The key user of a PLM system for all MAN plants.

### Electron

#### 3D Design Programmer 01.2016 - 09.2016 (9 months)

Minimized design process time for nonserial parts from 5 days to 3 minutes.

Brought a number of production failures caused by design to 0.

The automatized design process with C# and VisualBasic using mathematical models of each typical component.

## **Dirinler Foundry**

### Trainee Engineer 02.2015 - 11.2015 (9 months)

Worked as a blue staff worker and technician to understand the manufacturing environment and improve my communication skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

Mastercamp Strive School - Al Engineering

**BSc** Dokuz Eylül University, Mechanical Engineering

# **Strive School Solo Capstone Project - 2021**

### Intercoach (AI Interviewer)

<u>Intercoach</u> helps candidates to prepare for the job interviews. It gives typical interview questions, helps to practice answering them, and uses AI to measure the impression that you will give to the interviewer with your answers.

#### **BSc Graduation Project - 2015**

Mathematical Modeling of Production for Increasing Productivity //The Can Ozan Pano Project In this project, I developed an AI algorithm that calculates the possible production time and error rate of each production step.

#### **VOLUNTARY WORKS**

## 2012 - 2013 AEGEE Europe/ Education Working Group/ Speaker

The Education Working Group is the meeting point for students who are interested in European integration in the field of Higher Education and who would like to contribute to its development. I coordinated the education of the whole of AEGEE Europe's new and current members.

#### 2012 - 2013 Imbat Leo Club/ Founder Vice President

With Association of Spinal Cord Injuries - Blue Cover Project Team Leader With Karabağlar Municipality, Green Project Team Leader(Environmental Awareness, Conferences, Educations)

#### **SEMINARS and TRAININGS**

PMP-PMI

Bilge Adam 12.2018 (45 Hours)

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate

DeepLearning.Al Coursera - 08.2021 (80 Hours)

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

IBM Coursera - 02.2021 (132 Hours)

**AUX Istanbul** 

Autodesk - 06.10.2016

#### WHERE TO FIND ME / REFERENCES / PAPERS

Blog, GitHub, Personal Web Site, Linkedin, Glassdoor Resume References and Papers